Guide to the Walter W. and Lillian F. Norton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Walter W. and Lillian F. Norton papers
1898-1929
MS 1015
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
This collection is made up of the papers of Walter W. Norton and of his wife, Lillian Frances Reynolds Norton. Her papers reflect her work as chairwoman of the Liberty Loan Committee of Lakeville, Connecticut from 1917-1919 and contain correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, receipts, and other material from the various branches of the Committee. Walter W. Norton's papers consist of a bound manuscript genealogical record of the descendants of John Norton and Jane Cooper and letters (1910s-1920s) concerning his stamp collection.
Norton, Walter Whittlesey, 1867-1924
Immediate Source of Acquisition
By gift, 1943, and from the Holley Manufacturing Company Papers, purchased in 1946.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Walter W. and Lillian F. Norton Papers consist of materials relating to the World War I Liberty Loan, to the genealogy of the Norton family, and to stamp collecting. Included are correspondence, printed matter, receipts, and other papers.
The papers of Lillian Frances (Reynolds) Norton deal with her work as chairwoman of the Liberty Loan Committee of Lakeville, Connecticut, between 1917 and 1919. In her correspondence are circular letters, memoranda, printed forms, receipts, and other items from the Connecticut State Council of Defense, the Treasury Department, the National Woman's Liberty Loan Committee, and the Liberty Loan Committee of New England. There are, in addition, pamphlets, leaflets, newsletters, bulletins, manuals for loan salespeople, and a miscellany of other printed matter, certificates, and related materials.
The papers of Walter Whittlesey Norton (1867-1924), husband of Lillian F. Norton, fall into two parts. The first consists of a bound manuscript genealogical record of the descendants of John Norton and Jane Cooper, compiled between 1898 and 1924, accompanied by several items of correspondence and other papers. The remainder of Walter Norton's papers are letters, mainly from the nineteen-teens and nineteen-twenties, concerned with his stamp collection. Some printed matter and receipts are interfiled with the letters, which are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
The Norton genealogy was given to Yale University by the Collector's Shop in 1943; the rest of the papers were separated from the Holley Manufacturing Company Papers (Ms. Gr. No. 286), which were purchased for Yale in 1946. The latter collection was transferred to the University of Connecticut in 1980.
Stamp collectors -- United States; World War, 1914-1918; Norton, Lillian Frances Reynolds; Norton, Walter Whittlesey, 1867-1924; Norton family; Liberty Loan Committee (Lakeville, Conn.)
- Inventory
  - Lillian F. Norton: Liberty Loan Papers
    - Correspondence, 1917 December-1919 May (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
    - Pamphlets and leaflet, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Women's Committee Council of National Defense Newsletter, 1918 March-July (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Connecticut State Council of Defense Bulletin, 1918 March-December (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Manuals for salespeople, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1918, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Walter W. Norton
    - Genealogical record, 1898-1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Stamp collection correspondence, A-Y, [ca. 1910-1929] (Box 2, Folder 11 - 22)